Register of the Arthur T. Vanderbilt Political, Professional, and Judicial Papers, 1902 - 1957
Arthur T. Vanderbilt Political, Professional and Judicial Papers, 1902-1957
This collection contains correspondence, business records, litigation documents, teaching notes and materials, bulletins and reports, speeches, manuscript writings, photographs, financial records, books, clippings, scrapbooks, and ephemera documenting the life and career of Arthur T. Vanderbilt, and spans 1902 to 1957. It should be noted that the materials are vast, including drafts of judicial opinions over the last ten years of Vanderbilt's life. The first series on Education contains material pertaining to his education at Newark High School, Wesleyan University, and Columbia Law School. It also contains records and correspondence relating to Vanderbilt's Delta Kappa Epsilon Alumni Activities from 1925 to 1957, and correspondence relating to his service on the Wesleyan University Board of Trustees from 1934 to 1957 and as its President from 1946 to 1947. The Law Practice series consists of materials relating to Vanderbilt's private law practice, spanning 1914 to 1947. It includes client lists and litigation files, account books and other financial records, work records, briefs, and legal diaries. The New York University School of Law series documents Vanderbilt's roles there as both professor and dean, and spans 1914 to 1947. It contains teaching notes, correspondence, articles written by Vanderbilt and related materials, NYU statistical and administrative materials, reports and memos related to the NYU Law Center Institutes, materials related to the Root-Tilden Scholarship Program, Citizenship Clearing House, and Institute of Judicial Administration, as well as materials more generally related to NYU. The Political Activities series contains campaign records, correspondence, scrapbooks and clippings, reports and election statistics, and other materials related to Vanderbilt's political career, spanning the dates 1919 to 1947. The Bar Association Activities series contains correspondence related to Vanderbilt's term as president of the American Bar Association from 1936 to 1939 as well as more general correspondence, reports, and documentation of ABA activities from 1936 to 1957. It also contains a small amount of material on Essex County and New Jersey Bar Association correspondence from the 1930s and 1940s. The Judicial Reform and Administration of Justice series contains correspondence, articles and clippings, reports, and memos documenting the Attorney General's Committee on Administrative Procedure during the 1940s, administrative law, the New Jersey Judicial Council during the 1930s and 1940s, the National Conference of Judicial Councils from the 1930s to the 1950s, the Advisory Committee of the United States Supreme Court on Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure during the 1940s, the Committee on Military Justice for the War Department from 1946 to 1950, the National Committee on Traffic Law Enforcement from 1938 to 1951, the Hoover Commission on Reorganization of the Government, and the New Jersey Constitutional Revision Movement from 1940 to 1948. The Chief Justice of New Jersey series contains the judicial opinions, correspondence, clippings, and subject files from Vanderbilt's term, 1948 to 1957. The Folders of Engagements series contains invitations, correspondence and other related materials, spanning 1938 to 1957. The following three series: Book Reviews and Financial; Books, Articles, and Addresses; and Writings - Unfinished, contain published and unpublished writings by Vanderbilt as well as a small amount of financial papers. The final series, Miscellaneous: Photographs, Travel, and Personal Interests, contain materials documenting Vanderbilt's personal life as well as unidentified files.
Collection Arrangement
The papers are organized into twelve series: Education, 1902-1957; Law Practice, 1914-1947; New York University School of Law, 1914-1947; Political Activities, 1919-1947; Bar Association Activities; Judicial Reform and the Administration of Justice; Chief Justice of New Jersey, 1948-1957; Folders of Engagements; Book Reviews and Financial; Books, Articles and Addresses; Writings - Unfinished; and Miscellaneous: Photographs, Travel, Personal Interests. The series are primarily arranged by subject.
These papers were organized by Arthur T. Vanderbilt and his secretaries during his lifetime and placed in storage immediately after his death in 1957. They remained in storage in Summit, New Jersey until moved in bulk to Wesleyan in 1971. A true lifetime of record keeping meant that their rich quality was matched by their quantity, totaling 11,000 pounds.
Numerous books and bound serials not previously among its holdings have been catalogued and placed on the shelves on the Wesleyan University Library. A selection of duplicate books written or edited by Arthur T. Vanderbilt are retained in the Collection on Legal Change.
Boxes 185, 290-291, and 315 and 354 are no longer shelved with the collection and are considered missing. Their contents are listed in the detailed description of the collection below.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Vanderbilt, Arthur T., 1888-1957.; New Jersey. Supreme Court.; Delta Kappa Epsilon.; Columbia University. School of Law.; New York University. School of Law.; American Bar Association.; Justice, Administration of.; Practice of law.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Briefs (legal documents); New Jersey.; Administrative law.; United States. Supreme Court. Advisory Committee on Rules of Criminal Procedure.; Judicial records.; Law reform.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Alumni and alumnae.; Courts-martial and courts of inquiry--United States.; Mansfield, William Murray, Earl of, 1705-1793.; New Jersey--Politics and government.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Students.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Board of Trustees.; Political campaigns--New Jersey.
Related Material
Vanderbilt, Arthur T., II. "Paths to Justice: A Biography of Arthur T. Vanderbilt," 1972. Wesleyan University undergraduate thesis.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Education
  - Newark High School:, 1902-1905 (Box 1)
    - Scrapbook, Newark High School, 1902-1905 (Box 1)
  - Wesleyan University
    - Student:, 1906-1910 (Box 2)
      - Scrapbook, 1906-1910 (Box 2)
      - Course Notes, 1906-1910 (Box 3)
      - Correspondence, 1906-1920 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence, 1906-1920 (Box 5)
      - Photographs (Box 6)
        - Student life, 1906-1910 (Box 6)
        - Reunions, 1914-1956 (Box 6)
    - Delta Kappa Epsilon Alumni Activities:, 1925-1957 (Box 7)
      - Card Index File, Dekes, 1879-1957 (Box 7)
      - Correspondence, DKE fund raising activities, (3 folders), 1940 (Box 8)
      - DKE name cards, 1890-1957 (Box 9)
      - Correspondence (Box 9)
        - DKE undergraduate problems, 1939-1946 (Box 9)
        - DKE alumni problems, 1939-1951 (Box 9)
        - General, 1940 (Box 9)
        - General, 1943 (Box 9)
      - DKE Financial Statements (Box 10)
      - Bamburger-Macy Executive appraisal charts (Box 10)
      - Constitution of Gamma Phi (Box 10)
      - Correspondence, (arranged alphabetically), 1956-1957 (Box 10)
      - Correspondence, (8 folders), 1957-1957 (Box 11)
    - Board of Trustees and Presidential files, 1934-1957 (Box 12)
      - Correspondence with Executive Committees #1-3, 1946-1948 (Box 12)
      - Committee on Faculty and Curriculum, 1940-1947 (Box 13)
      - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 14)
      - Correspondence, Committee on selecting new president (Box 14)
      - Correspondence and materials, Wesleyan University Institute of Public Affairs (Box 14)
      - Correspondence, Alumni Association Committee on Revision of Constitution (Box 14)
      - Correspondence and materials, student elections, 1946 (Box 14)
      - Minutes of Board and Committee meetings (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, memos, etc., (2 folders), 1945-1957 (Box 14)
      - Correspondence (alphabetically arranged), 1935-1937 (Box 15)
      - Correspondence regarding Class of 1910's 25th reunion, 1935 (Box 16)
      - Correspondence (alphabetically arranged), 1938-1939 (Box 16)
      - Correspondence (2 folders), 1946 (Box 17)
      - Correspondence (4 folders alphabetically arranged), 1947-1951 (Box 18)
      - Correspondence (alphabetically arranged), 1952-1957 (Box 19)
    - Columbia Law School, 1910-1913 (Box 20)
      - Course Notes, 1910-1913 (Box 20)
- Law Practice: 1914-1947
  - Card File. Clients and cases. (Box 21)
  - Eminent Members of the Bench and Bar, 1917 (Box 21)
  - Name and Address files (3 folders) (Box 22)
  - Account book of costs and cases, 1914-1915 (Box 23)
  - Litigation files (20 files), 1917-1921 (Box 23)
  - Attorney bank statements, 1922-1926 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence and bank statements, 1924-1927 (Box 24)
  - Office equipment and bills (Box 24)
  - Office data, 1936 (Box 24)
  - Paid bills, 1938 (Box 24)
  - Expenses and overtime, 1938 (Box 24)
  - Expenses and overtime, 1938 (Box 25)
  - Work records, 1937-1939 (Box 25)
  - Invitations declined, 1939-1945 (Box 25)
  - Congratulations, 1943-1947 (Box 25)
  - Babcock v. Babcock, 1931 (Box 26)
  - Armitage, Blaicher et al. v. Stamler, 1932 (Box 26)
  - Collins v. International Alliance, 1932 (Box 26)
  - Totten v. Lehman, 1933 (Box 26)
  - Pulaski Trucking Co. v. Newark Milk Co., 1936
  - Lincoln Mfg. Co. Investigation, 1938 (Box 26)
  - Butts v. Hudson Trust Co. (Box 26)
  - Scrapbook, Public Fire Insurance Company, 1928-1931 (Box 27)
  - Clippings from Journal of Commerce, 1936-1939 (Box 27)
  - Clippings and articles, Insurance Trusts (Box 27)
  - Insurance: Use and occupation (Box 27)
  - Insurance: fire, defenses, and clauses (Box 27)
  - Contemporary Law Pamphlets, 1937-1943 (Box 27)
  - Briefs (8 volumes) United States v. R. H. Michner, 1943 (Box 28)
  - Legal Diaries, 1938-1947 (Box 29)
- New York University School of Law: Professor, 1914-1947; Dean, 1943-1947
  - Teaching Notes (Box 31-35)
  - Correspondence, September 1945-August 1946 (Box 36)
  - Correspondence (F-T), September 1947-December 1948 (Box 37)
  - Correspondence(U-Z), September 1947-December 1948 (Box 38)
  - Correspondence, January 1949-December 1950 (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 40)
  - Annual Survey of American Law (Box 41)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1947 (Box 41)
    - Administrative Law articles by ATV (correspondence, research, drafts), 1942-1945 (Box 42)
    - Administrative Law articles: by ATV, replies from states (2 folders), 1945 (Box 43)
    - Cases by Hoelper, 1945 (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous (2 folders), 1946 (Box 43)
    - Articles on War Powers by ATV (correspondence, research, drafts), 1942-1943 (Box 44)
    - War Power articles, 1943-1946 (Box 45)
    - Articles on Administration of Justice, Courts and Law Reform, 1942-1944 (Box 46)
    - Articles on Legal Education and Bar Organization by ATV (correspondence, research, drafts), 1942-1947 (Box 47)
    - NYU Conference (Box 47)
      - Alien Property Custodian (Box 47)
      - War Contracts Termination, October 1944 (Box 47)
      - War Contracts (Box 47)
      - Pension Plan (Box 47)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1955 (Box 48)
    - Foreword. Topical Index, Jacket, 1942-1946 (Box 48)
    - State War Legislation, Materials, 1940-1943 (Box 48)
    - Annual Survey, Clippings (Box 48)
    - Dinner, Lotus Club, 1946 (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous materials and notes for Annual Survey (6 files), 1942-1948 (Box 49)
  - NYU Statistical and Descriptive Materials (Box 50)
    - Bulletins, 1945-1946 (Box 50)
    - Miscellaneous bulletins (Box 50)
    - Deans Report, 1947-1948 (Box 50)
    - Bulletins, Miscellaneous (Box 51)
    - Bulletins, Miscellaneous (Box 52)
    - Statistics, 1942-1948 (Box 53)
    - Self Survey Materials (5 files), 1956 (Box 54)
    - Self Survey Materials (5 files), 1956 (Box 55)
  - Law Center (Box 56)
    - Reports: "NYU Plans a Great Law Center"; Report of Dean, 1943-1944; Report of Dean, 1944-1945, 1943-1945 (Box 56)
    - Law Center Building Campaign, correspondence and clippings (Box 56)
    - Financial memos, 1943-1945 (Box 56)
    - Washington Square South Project (Box 56)
    - Schwend Loan Fund (Box 56)
    - Photos of Faculty, Alumni, and new building (Box 56)
    - Washington Square South (Box 56)
    - Law School Drive, literature and form letters sent to alumni (Box 57)
    - Weekly reports. daily reports, dinner lists, lists of judges (Box 57)
    - Foundations, corporations publicity, Advisory Council, inventory (Box 57)
    - Dinners, 1946-1947 (Box 57)
    - Card Index Files (2). Contributors to the Law Center Drive (Box 58)
  - Law Center Institutes (Box 59)
    - Administrative Law Institute (Box 59)
    - Inter-American Law Institute (2 folders) (Box 59)
    - Institute of International Law (Box 59)
    - Food Law Institute (Box 59)
    - Insurance Law Institute (Box 59)
    - Institute of Public Affairs (Box 59)
    - Institute of Comparative Law (Box 59)
    - Transportation Institute (Box 59)
    - Transportation Literature, 1944 (Box 60)
    - Correspondence, Transportation, 1946 (Box 60)
    - Institute on Money and the Law (Box 60)
  - Root-Tilden Scholarship Program (Box 61)
    - Correspondence, formation of the first committee, 1951-1952 (Box 61)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous materials, lists, memos, grades (Box 61)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous materials, lists, grades, memos (Box 62)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 62)
  - Citizenship Clearing House (Box 63)
    - Financial backing, Falk Foundation, 1951-1954 (Box 63)
    - Application to Ford Foundation (Box 63)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1951 (Box 64)
    - Correspondence (alphabetically arranged), 1951-1957 (Box 65)
    - Articles, materials, memos (2 files), 1952-1953 (Box 66)
    - Memos, articles from others, 1947-1951 (Box 67)
    - ATV speeches, reports, miscellaneous memos and lists (Box 67)
    - Speech materials (Box 67)
    - ATV active folder on CCH (Box 68)
    - American Political Science Association form letters, 1947-1950 (Box 68)
    - Moley Manuscript (Box 68)
    - Professor O. Garfield Jones (Box 68)
    - New Jersey College for Women (Box 68)
  - Institute of Judicial Administration (Box 69)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1957 (Box 69)
    - Publications (Box 70, 72a)
    - Names, pamphlets, lists, forms (Box 70)
    - Traffic Law Enforcement, 1953-1954 (Box 71)
    - N.Y. Temporary Commission on the Courts, correspondence, clippings and articles (Box 71)
    - Card Index Files (2), proposed membership (Box 72)
  - Miscellaneous Files (Box 73)
    - Sack tenure case (3 files) (Box 73)
    - Administrative Law Seminar, correspondence, 1946 (Box 74)
    - Felker, Arthur F. (Box 74)
    - New England Auto Products Corporation (Sedgwick) (Box 74)
    - Temporary Criminal Law (Box 74)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings re NYU (Box 74)
    - NYU examinations, undated (Box 75)
    - Law Library (Box 75)
    - Legal Bibliography (Box 75)
    - Annotated Law Catalog (Box 75)
    - Legislation (Box 75)
    - Survey of Family Law (Box 75)
    - Model Code of Criminal Law (Box 75)
    - Notes of Dean de Sloovere's lectures on the Interpretation of Statutes and cases (Box 75)
    - Jurisprudence notes--de Sloovere's (Box 75)
    - 57th Annual Dinner, "Leadership and the Law School" ATV, January 25, 1944 (Box 76)
    - Correspondence re Law, Review (Box 76)
    - NYU Council meeting notes, 1948-1950 (Box 76)
    - InterProfession Conference on Education for Professional Responsibility, 1947-1950 (Box 76)
    - NYU proposal to Ford Foundation, 1956 (Box 76)
    - Carnegie Foundation for Advancement of Teaching (2 files) (Box 77)
    - Refresher Courses (Box 78)
    - Research on Legislation (Box 78)
    - Scholarships (Box 78)
    - Space (Box 78)
    - Tax Law Review (Box 78)
    - Conference on Tax Procedures (Box 78)
    - Teaching Methods (Box 78)
    - Traffic Institute (Box 78)
    - Transportation Institute (Box 78)
    - Ludwig Teller (Box 78)
    - Sommer Library (Box 78)
    - Advisory Council to President Eisenhower's Action (Box 78)
    - Committee for Traffic Safety (Box 78)
    - Pogson, Henry (Box 78)
    - NYU History (Box 79)
    - Honors Courses (Box 79)
    - Institutes (Box 79)
    - Institutes for Improving Administration of Justice, 1944-1945 (Box 79)
    - Labor Law (Box 79)
    - Library (Box 79)
    - Moot Courts (Box 79)
    - Office Practice (Box 79)
    - Placements (Box 79)
    - Patent Law and Cartels (Box 79)
    - Profit sharing plan conference (Box 79)
    - Pre-bar association (Box 79)
    - Procedure (Box 79)
    - Publications (Box 79)
    - Institute of Public Law and Administration (Box 79)
    - NYU Law School Bulletins (Box 79)
    - Curriculum Revision (Box 80)
    - Faculty (Box 80)
    - Institute on Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (Box 80)
    - Field Centenary (Box 80)
    - Graduate Division (Box 80)
    - Administrative Law Symposium (Box 80)
    - Board of Visitors (Box 80)
    - Bar Association, study of Casebooks (Box 80)
    - Competition and standards (Box 80)
    - Catalogs (Box 80)
- Political Activities: 1919-1947
  - Campaign fund record, 1919 (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, William Runyon gubernatorial race, 1919, 1922 (Box 81)
  - Runyon dinners (Box 81)
  - Campaign manager reports, 1920, 1922 (Box 81)
  - Campaign circulars (Box 81)
  - Runyon campaign finances (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, 1922-1930 (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, campaign of 1930. 3 loose-leaf note books, 2 notebooks of clippings; all 5 center on the Dwight Morrow senatorial campaign (Box 82)
  - Correspondence, David Baird gubernatorial campaign, 1931 (Box 83)
  - Clippings, 1931 (Box 83)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 83)
  - Clippings, 1932 (Box 83)
  - Clippings (2 folders), 1933 (Box 84)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1934 (Box 84)
  - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 85)
  - Clippings, 1934 (Box 85)
  - Campaign Scrapbooks, 1934 (Box 86)
  - Campaign Scrapbooks, 1934 (Box 87)
  - Campaign Scrapbooks, 1934 (Box 88)
  - Election Statistics, 1929-1939 (Box 89, 380)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, 1934-1935 (Box 89)
  - Journal of Commerce clippings, 1935 (Box 89)
  - Clippings, uncut, 1935 (Box 89)
  - Legislation, 1935 (Box 89)
  - Audit reports, 1935 (Box 90)
  - Clippings, 1935 (Box 90)
  - Clippings, 1936 (Box 91)
  - Memos re Essex Board of Freeholders (Box 92)
  - Clippings, 1936-1938 (Box 92)
  - Clippings, 1938-1939 (Box 93)
  - Clippings, 1940 January-June (Box 94)
  - Clippings, 1940 July-December (Box 95)
  - Governor Harold G. Hoffman (Box 96)
  - Frank Hague, clippings (Box 96)
  - Hague, clippings, correspondence re McKean's book, Boss Hague (Box 96)
  - Clippings, Frank Hague Jr. appointment to Court of Errors and Appeals (Box 96)
  - Wendell Willkie, Third term literature, 1940 (Box 97)
  - Wendell Willkie, Campaign correspondence and clippings (2 folders) (Box 97)
  - Robert C. Hendrickson, senator, clippings, correspondence, (2 folders), 1940 (Box 98)
  - Clippings, 1939-1941 (Box 99)
  - Clippings (column, The Drum Beat of Politics), 1936-1942 (Box 100)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 100)
  - Clippings, 1942 (Box 100)
  - Correspondence, Dewey presidential campaign, 1941-1943 (Box 101)
  - Clippings re Dewey campaign, 1943-1944 (Box 101)
  - Correspondence, Dewey, 1944-1947 (Box 101)
  - Correspondence, Dewey campaign, 1944 (Box 101)
  - Clippings, Dewey campaign, June-December 1944 (Box 101)
  - Primary ballots, Essex County, 1944 (Box 102)
  - Clippings, 1943 (Box 103)
  - Miscellaneous, 1943-1944 (Box 103)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 104)
  - Correspondence re city of Newark, 1938-1946 (Box 105)
  - Clippings re Newark, 1944-1945 (Box 105)
  - Miscellaneous data re Newark (Box 105)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 106)
  - Clippings, 1945 (Box 106)
  - Correspondence, Thomas H. Reed, 1944-1945 (Box 107)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 107)
  - Edgar Rossbach (Box 108)
  - Correspondence and clippings, Walter Van Riper, 1942-1946 (Box 108)
  - Clippings, 1945-1947 (Box 108)
  - Correspondence, George Biehl, 1946 (Box 109)
  - Correspondence, materials, Gov. Alfred E. Driscoll, 1946-1952 (Box 109)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 110)
  - New Jersey government materials (2 folders) (Box 111)
  - Fallen; Salmon; memos re conflicts with judicial duties (Box 112)
  - Essex County miscellaneous voting records, 1919-1935 (Box 112)
  - Essex County cartoons, 1921-1936 (Box 112)
  - Clean Government v. original Clean Government (Box 112)
  - Drafts of "Twenty Years of Government in Essex County, New Jersey" (Box 112)
  - Report of the Republican County Committee of Essex, 1933 (Box 112)
  - Clippings (Box 112)
  - Truman administration, miscellaneous clippings (Box 112)
  - Clippings re Dewey, Salmon; miscellaneous clippings from Buffalo Law Journal (Box 112)
  - Records of State Finance Committee (Box 112)
- Bar Association Activities
  - American Bar Association: President, 1937-1938
    - Correspondence, 1936-1938
      - General correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 113)
      - Correspondence, public relations, 1937 (Box 113)
      - Correspondence, September 1936-September 1937 (Box 113)
      - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 113)
      - General correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 114)
      - Correspondence regarding Committee, 1937 (Box 114)
      - General correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 114)
      - Correspondence, A-C, 1937-1938 (Box 115)
      - Correspondence, D-F, 1937-1938 (Box 115)
      - Correspondence, G-H, 1937-1938 (Box 116)
      - Correspondence, I-L, 1937-1938 (Box 116)
      - Correspondence, M-O, 1937-1938 (Box 117)
      - Correspondence, P-R, 1937-1938 (Box 117)
      - Correspondence, R-S, 1937-1938 (Box 118)
      - Correspondence, S-T, 1937-1938 (Box 118)
      - Correspondence, U-V, 1937-1938 (Box 119)
      - Correspondence, W-Z, 1937-1938 (Box 119)
    - Correspondence, arranged by state (Box 120)
      - Alabama-Indiana, 1937-1938 (Box 120)
      - Iowa-Montana, 1937-1938 (Box 120)
      - Nebraska-North Dakota, 1937-1938 (Box 120)
      - Ohio-Virginia, 1937-1938 (Box 120)
    - Correspondence, 1937-1938
      - ABA, 1937 (Box 121)
      - Correspondence regarding Cleveland Annual Meeting, 1938 (Box 121)
      - ABA, 1937-1938 (Box 121)
      - ABA Correspondence, March 1937-September 1938 (Box 121)
    - Correspondence. Congratulations upon nomination as president of ABA, and upon completion of term, 1937-1938 (Box 122)
      - Congratulations upon election and retirement as president of ABA (Box 122)
      - Congratulations upon election as president of ABA (Box 122)
      - Congratulations upon election and retirement as president of ABA (Box 122)
      - Luncheons and dinner, 1937 (Box 122)
      - Congratulations, election as president of ABA (Box 122)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1939
      - Correspondence, September 1938-January 1939, H-M (Box 123)
      - Correspondence, September 1938-July 1939, C-G (Box 123)
      - Correspondence, September 1938-July 1939, N-S (Box 123)
      - Correspondence, September 1938-July 1939, T-Z (Box 123)
      - Correspondence, September 1938-June 1939 [2 folders] (Box 123)
    - Luncheon and dinner engagements, 1937-1938 (Box 124)
  - American Bar Association: General (Box 125)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1957 (Box 125)
    - Alphabetical list of members, "Economics of Legal Profession,", 1937-1938 (Box 126)
    - Committee on refresher courses (Box 126)
    - List of committees and active members (Box 126)
    - Pre-legal education, 1941 (Box 126)
    - Answers to questionnaires (Box 126)
    - Canada (Box 126)
    - American Bar Foundation, correspondence, reports, reports of research and library committee (Box 127)